the following content is provided under a Creative Commons license
以下内容是根据Creative Commons授权提供
your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to offer
您的支持将有助于麻省理工学院开放式课程继续报价
high-quality educational resources for free
免费优质教育资源
to make a donation or view additional materials from hundreds of them IT
进行捐赠或查看附加材料由数百人资讯
courses
课程
visit MIT OpenCourseWare at 0 CW
参观麻省理工学院开放式课程在0 CW
that MIT that EDU home the
麻省理工学院的EDU家
the
该
the in
在该
the norm
规范
are the in discussing the
是在讨论
continuous-time and discrete-time Fourier transforms we
连续时间和离散时间傅里叶变换，我们
developed a number of important properties
开发了一些重要性质
to particularly sitting significant ones as I mention
特别是要坐显著那些为我提
at the time are the modulation property and the convolution property
在当时的调制特性和卷积性质
starting with the next lecture the one after this one
在开始下一个演讲后这一个一个
will be developing and exploiting some other consequences
将开发和利用某些其他后果
the modulation property in today's lecture though I'd like to
在今天的讲座的调制特性，虽然我想
review and expand on the notion of filtering
审查和扩大对过滤的概念
which as I had mentioned flows more less directly from
这正如我所提到的流动更加少直接从
the convolution property to begin let me just quickly review
卷积财产，开始让我快速回顾
what the convolution property is both for continuous-time
卷积性质是什么都为连续时间
and for discrete-time the convolution property tells us
和离散时间卷积属性告诉我们
that the 48 transform
该48变换
all the convolution up to time functions
所有的卷积最多时间的函数
is the product up to 48 transforms
是产品达48转换
now what this means
现在这是什么意思
in terms love linear time-invariant filters
在爱情方面线性时不变滤波器
since we know that the in the time domain the output of a linear
因为我们知道在时域中的线性的输出
time-invariant filter is the convolution
时间不变滤波器的卷积
love the input and the impulse response
爱的输入和脉冲响应
it says essentially then in the frequency domain
说，实质上然后在频域中
that the forty a transformer the output is the product
该40的变压器的输出是产品
of the 48 transform of the impulse response
48的变换的脉冲响应的
namely the frequency response and the Fourier transform
即，频率响应和傅立叶变换
love the input so the output is described through that product
爱的输入，使输出通过产品描述
now recall also
现在回忆起来还
bad in developing the four EA transform I interpreted
在发展的四个EA变换糟糕了，我的解释
the Fourier transform as the complex amplitude
的傅立叶变换为复数振幅
over decomposition of the signal interns have a set of complex exponentials
在信号实习生的分解有一组复指数
and the frequency response for the convolution property
以及用于卷积特性的频率响应
in effect tells us what the amplitudes how to modify the amplitudes
实际上告诉我们的振幅如何修改振幅
avi to those complex exponentials as they go through the system
avi到那些复杂的指数函数，因为他们去通过系统
now this led to the notion of filtering
现在这导致过滤的概念
where the basic concept was that since we can modify
那里的基本概念是，既然我们可以修改
the airport to %uh each of the exponential
机场到％呃每个指数的
complex exponential components separately weekend for example
复指数成份分开周末为例
retain some love them and totally eliminate others
保留一些爱他们，完全消除其他
and this is the basic notion of filtering so
这是滤波的基本概念，所以
we have as you recall first evolved the notion
我们为你还记得第一次进化的概念
in continuous-time all an ideal filter
在连续时间所有的理想过滤器
for example I L a straight year an ideal
例如I L直线一年的理想
low-pass filter where we pass exactly
低通滤波器，我们确切地传递
frequency comp phone it's in one band and reject
频率排版的手机是在一个乐队，并拒绝
totally frequency comp ponents in another band
在另一波段全频排版ponents
the van being passed of course referred to as the passband
在传递过程中的搬运车称作通带
and the ban rejected as the stopping I
该禁令拒绝为我停止
illustrated here low pass filter we can of course
这里所示的低通滤波器，我们当然可以
reject the low frequencies and retain
拒绝低频率和保留
the high frequencies and that then corresponds to
高频率和然后对应于
ideal high pass filter or we can just retain frequencies within a band
理想高通滤波器，或者我们可以只保留一个频段内的频率
and so I show below what is referred to commonly as
所以我在下面显示什么被称为俗称
a bandpass filter now
一个带通滤波器现在
this is what the ideal filters look like
这是理想的过滤器看起来像
for continuous-time for discrete-time we have exactly
在连续时间的离散时间，我们有完全相同
the same situation namely we have
同样的情况，即我们有
an ideal discrete-time low-pass filter which
一个理想的离散时间低通滤波器，
passes exactly frequencies which are the low frequencies
通过哪些是低频频率完全相同
low frequencies of course being around zero and because the periodicity also
当然，低频率是在零附近并且由于周期性还
around 2pi
各地2PI
we show also an ideal
我们展示也是一个理想的
high pass filter and a high pass filter
高通滤波器和一个高通滤波器
as i indicated last time passes frequencies around pie
正如我上次绕过馅饼频率
and finally below that I show an ideal
终于下面我展示一个理想的
bandpass filter a an ideal bandpass filter passing frequencies
带通滤波器一个理想的带通滤波器的频率传递
someplace in the range between 0 and pie
在某处的范围介于0和馅饼
and recall also bat the basic difference between
还记得蝙蝠之间的基本区别
continuous-time and discrete-time for these filters is that
连续时间和离散时间对这些过滤器是
the discrete-time versions are of course periodic
离散时间版本当然周期性
in frequency now let's look at
在频率现在让我们来看看
these ideal filters and in particular the idea low-pass filter
这些理想的过滤器，特别是构思的低通滤波器
in the time domain we have
在时域中，我们有
the frequency response 0 the idea low-pass filter
频率响应0想法的低通滤波器
and shown below it is the impulse response so here is the frequency
并显示它下面是脉冲响应所以这里的频率
response
响应
and below it the impulse response
和其下的脉冲响应
love the ideal low-pass filter
爱的理想低通滤波器
and this of course is a sin x over X
这当然是一种罪x的基于X
for with impulse response and recognize also
与脉冲响应并承认
or recall that since this frequency response
或者记得，因为这个频率响应
is real value
是真正的价值
the impulse response in other words the inverse transform
换句话说，逆变换的脉冲响应
is an even function of time and
是偶函数的时间和
notice also since I want to refer back to this
还注意到，因为我想重提这一
that the impulse response to an ideal Lopez filter
这与理想洛佩兹滤波器的脉冲响应
in fact is non causal that follows from Long other things from the fact that
实际上是非因果遵循从事实龙其他的东西，
it's an even function
它是一个偶函数
but keep in mind in fact that sin x over its function
但要记住的是，罪恶倍过它的功能
goes off to infinity in both directions so
在两个方向使熄灭到无限远
the impulse response to the idea low-pass filter
这一想法的低通滤波器的脉冲响应
is symmetric and continues to have tales of the plus and minus infinity
是对称的，并继续具有正负无穷大的故事
now the situation is basically the same
现在的情况是基本相同
in the discrete-time case
在离散时间情况
let's look at the frequency response and associated impulse response
让我们来看看的频率响应和相关的脉冲响应
for an ideal discrete-time low-pass filter
对于一个理想的离散时间低通滤波器
so once again here is the
所以再次在这里是
frequency response love the idea low-pass filter
频率响应爱的想法低通滤波器
and below it I show the impulse response
和它下面我展示的脉冲响应
again its a sin x over x-type impulse response
再次它是一种罪过x在X型脉冲响应
and again we recognize
我们再次认识
that sits in the frequency domain this frequency response
在频域中，它位于该频率响应
is real bad that means as a consequence
是真正的坏，这意味着作为一个后果
of the properties love the forty a transforming inverse Fourier transform
的性质爱40一个转化傅立叶逆变换
that the impulse response is an even function
该脉冲响应是一个偶函数
in the time domain and also incidently
在时域中，也顺便说一句
the sin x over expulsion goes off to infinity
罪x在驱逐熄灭到无限远
again in both directions
再次在两个方向上
now we talked about i do. filters
现在我们谈到了我做的。过滤器
in this discussion and ideal filters are
在这个讨论和理想的滤波器
in fact ideal in a certain sense what they do ideally
其实理想在一定意义上他们做什么理想
is they pass a certain band of frequencies exactly
他们是通过频率的某些频段正好
and they reject a band of frequencies exactly
他们拒绝频率的波段恰好
on the other hand there are many filtering problems in which
另一方面也有很多的过滤问题，其中
generally we don't have a sharp distinction between the frequencies we
一般我们没有频率截然区分我们
want to
要
passed in the frequencies you wanna 12 reject
在你要12拒绝的频率传递
one example if this that's elaborated on in the tax is
一个例子，如果这是的阐述了在税
the design of an automotive suspension system which in fact
汽车悬挂系统的设计而实际上
is the design all a low-pass filter
是设计中的所有的低通滤波器
and basically what you want to do in a case like that
基本上你想在这样的情况下什么
is filter out or attenuate
被过滤掉或减弱
very rapid Road variations and keep
非常快速路的变化，并保持
the lower variations in of course elevation of the highway
在高速公路的过程中海拔较低的变化
or or road and what you can see
或或道路，哪些是你可以看到
intuitively is dead and there isn't really a very sharp
直观地死了，是不是真的很犀利
distinction a sharp cutoff between what you would like to recall
你们之间想回顾什么区别一个锐截止
the low frequencies and what you would call the high frequencies
低频率，你会叫高频率
now also somewhat related to this is the fact dead
现在也有点关系的，这是事实，死
the as we've seen in the time domain is ideal filters have
的，因为我们已经看到了在时域是理想的过滤器有
very particular kind of character for example let's look back
很特别的那种性格的例子，让我们回顾一下
at the ideal low-pass filter and
在理想的低通滤波器和
we saw this the impulse response
我们看到这个脉冲响应
the impulse response is what we've shown here let's now look
脉冲响应是我们在这里显示，让我们现在来看看
at the step response love the discrete-time
在阶跃响应爱的离散时间
ideal low-pass filter and noticed the fact that it has a tail that oscillates
理想的低通滤波器，发现它有一个尾部，振荡的事实
and when this step its in fact it has oscillatory behavior
而当这一步了，其实它有振荡行为
now exactly the same situation occurs
现在完全一样的情况发生
in continuous-time let's look at the
在连续时间让我们来看看
step response love the continuous-time
阶跃响应爱的连续时间
ideal ok pass filter and
理想OK通滤波器和
what we see is that when a step its
我们看到的是，当其步
then in fact we get and isolation
那么实际上我们得到和隔离
and very often that isolation
而且很多时候隔离
is something this undesirable for example if you're designing
就是这个东西不理想的例子，如果你正在设计
an automotive suspension system and you hit a curve which is
汽车悬挂系统和你打的曲线是
step input in fact you probably would not like
阶跃输入，其实你可能会不喜欢
to have the automobile oscillating sort
有汽车振荡排序
sort dying down in in isolation
排序平息在隔离
now is another very important point which again
现在是另一个很重要的一点，再次
we can see there in continuous-time and discrete-time
我们可以在连续时间和离散时间看到有
which is that even if we wanted to have
这是，即使我们想有
an ideal filter the ideal filter has another problem
理想滤波器的理想滤波器具有另一个问题
if we want to attempt to implemented in real time
如果我们想尝试实时实现
what's the problem the problem is
出了什么问题，问题是
that since the impulse responses even and in fact
，由于脉冲响应甚至和实际上
has details that go of the plus and minus infinity
有一个去加号和减号无穷的细节
its non causal so if in fact
其非因果，所以如果在事实上
we want to build a filter and the filter is restricted operate in real time
我们要建立一个过滤器和过滤器被限制实时操作
than in fact we can't build
比实际上我们不能建造
an ideal filter so
一个理想的过滤器，以便
what that says is that in practice although i do. filters
什么，说的是，在实践中，虽然我做的。过滤器
are nice to think about and perhaps relate to practical problems
是不错的考虑，也许涉及到实际问​​题
more typically what we consider
更典型的是我们认为
are non-ideal filters and
在非理想滤波器和
in the discrete-time case non-ideal filter
在离散时间情况下的非理想滤波器
then would have a characteristic somewhat
然后就会有一个特点，有些
like i've indicated here where instead o
就像我在这里表示其中代替邻
a very rapid transition from passband to stop and
从通一个非常快速过渡到停止，
there would be more gradual transition
将有更多的渐变过渡
with a passband cutoff frequency and
具有通带截止频率和
a stop and cutoff frequency
停止和截止频率
and perhaps also instead of having exactly
也许，而不必也正是
flat characteristic in the stop band and in the past and
在阻带和过去平坦的特性和
we would allow a certain amount a ripple
我们将允许一定量的波动
we also have exactly the same situation
我们也有相同的情况，
in continuous-time we're here will just simply change your frequency axis
在连续时间，我们在这里只是简单地改变你的频率轴
to a continuous frequency axis instead of the discrete frequency axes
到一个连续的频率轴，而不是离散的频率轴
again we would think in terms of I'm allowable passband ripple
我们再次在条款想起我允许通带纹波
a transition from stop and from passband to stop and
从停止，并从通停止与过渡
with a passband cutoff frequency and a stop and
具有通带截止频率和一个停止和
cutoff frequency so
截止频率，使
kind of the notion here is dead again i do. filters are ideal in some respects
种在这里的概念是死的，我再次做。过滤器是理想的，在某些方面
not ideal in other respects and for many
在其他方面，对许多不理想
practical problems we may not want them and even if we did want them
实际的问题，我们可能不希望他们即使我们没要他们
we may not be able to get them perhaps because at this issue of causality
我们未必能得到他们也许是因为在这个问题上的因果关系
even if causality is not an issue what happens
即使因果关系不是一个问题，会发生什么
in filter design and implementation in fact
在滤波器的设计，事实上实施
is dead the sharper you attempt to make the cut off
死了更清晰的尝试，使切断
the more expensive in some sense the filter becomes
在某种意义上过滤器变得更昂贵
either in terms of comp phone-ins in continuous-time
无论是在排版手机插件在连续时间条件
or in terms of computation in discrete-time
或在计算在离散时间方面
and so their are these whole variety of issues
，因此他们的这些品种全的问题
that really make it important to
，真正使很重要
understand the notion love non-ideal
理解这一概念的爱非理想
filters now just two
过滤器现在只有两个
illustrate as an example let me remind you
说明作为一个例子，让我提醒你
love one kinda bad example love what in fact is a non-ideal
只爱一个有点坏榜样，热爱自己其实是一个非理想
low-pass filter and we have look previously
低通滤波器和我们以​​前看
at The Associated differential equation
在相关的微分方程
let me now in fact related to a circuit
让我现在其实涉及到一个电路
and in particular an RC circuit
特别是一个RC电路
where the output could either be across the capacitor
当输出既可以是电容两端
or the output can be across the resistor so
或输出可以是电阻两端以便
effect we have two systems here we have a system
实际上，我们有两个系统在这里我们有一个系统
which is the system function from the voltage source input to the capacitor
这是从电压源输入到电容的系统功能
output
产量
the system from the both source input
该系统由两个源输入
to the resistor output and in fact
到电阻器输出，实际上
just up like your cause both its law to this we can relate those in a very
只是像你的事业无论其法律这一点，我们可以与那些在很
straightforward way
简单的方法
it's very straight forward to verify that
这是非常简单的验证
the system from input to resist their output
该系统从输入到抗蚀其输出
is simply the identity system with
是简单地用身份识别系统
the capacitor output subtracted from
电容输出减去
now we can write the differential equation
现在我们可以写微分方程
for either the system's and as we talked about last time
无论是系统的和我们谈到最后一次
in the last several lectures solve that equation using
在过去的几次讲座使用解决方程
the exploiting the properties at a4e a transform
所述A4E一个剥削性质变换
and in fact we if we look at the differential equation
而事实上，我们如果看微分方程
relating the capacitor output to
关于电容输出
the voltage source input we recognize that this is an example
电压源的输入，我们认识到这是一个例子
that in effect we saw previously and so
在影响我们先前等等看
just working our way down applying the 48 transport to the differential
只是我们的工作方式下应用48运输到差分
equation
方程
and generating the system function by taking the ratio of the capacitor
并通过采取该电容器的比率产生系统功能
voltage
电压
or its Fourier transform to the Fourier transform the source
或它的傅立叶变换的傅立叶变换的源
we then have the system function Associated
我们然后有关联的系统功能
with the system for which the output is the capacitor voltage
同的量，输出是电容电压的系统
or if we solve instead for the system function
或者，如果我们解决，而不是为系统函数
associated with the resistor output
与电阻器的输出相关联的
we can simply subtract h1 from unity
我们可以简单地从团结减去H1
and the system function that we get in that case is the system function
而我们在这种情况下，得到的系统的功能是在系统功能
that I show here so we have
我在这里展示，所以我们有
now to system functions one for the capacitor output
现在的系统功能之一的输出电容
the other for the resistor output and
其它的电阻器的输出和
one the first corresponding to the capacitor output
1第一对应于电容器的输出
in fact if we plotted on a linear ramp up to scale
事实上，如果我们绘制在一个线性斜坡上升到规模
looks like this and as you can see and as we saw last time
看起来是这样的，正如你可以看到，当我们看到最后一次
is an approximation to a low pass filter
是一个近似的低通滤波器
it is in fact and non-ideal ok pass filter
它实际上是与非理想确定通滤波器
whereas the resistor output is
而电阻输出
an approximation to a high pass filter
一个近似的高通滤波器
or in effect and non-ideal high pass filter
或在效应和非理想的高通滤波器
so in one case just comparing the two we have
因此，在一种情况下只比较这两个我们
a low-pass filter as the capacitor output associate with the capacitor
一个低通滤波器，作为电容器输出准与电容器
output
产量
and a high pass filter Associated with the
和伴有的高通滤波器
resistor out let's just quickly
电阻出来就让我们赶紧
look at that example now looking on a boat reply
看看这个例子现在正在寻找在船上答复
instead o on the linear scale that we showed before
代替邻对我们之前显示的线性度
and recall incidently a and
并记得顺便说一句一和
be aware incident leave the fact that week and of course cascade
要知道事件离开当然级联的事实，周
several filters if this type and approve the characteristics
几个过滤器，如果这种类型及批准特点
so I have shown at the top
所以我已经显示在顶部
a bodie plot or the
一个博迪情节或
capacitors system functions associated with the capacitor output it's flat out
与电容输出电容相关的系统功能很平了
to a frequency corresponding 21
对应21的频率
over the time constant RC
在时间常数RC
and then it falls off at 10 DB
然后将其在10 DB脱落
per decade a decade being a factor 10
每十年十年身为因素10
or if instead we looked at the system function associated with the resistor
或者相反，我们看着与电阻相关的系统功能
output that corresponds to a
对应于输出
10 dB per decade increase in frequency
每十年增加频率10分贝
up to approximately the reciprocal at the time constant and
高达约倒数的时间常数和
then approaching a flat characteristic after that
再之后，趋近平坦的特性
and if we consider either one of these
如果我们考虑这些任何一个
looking back again at the low-pass
再回首低通
filter if we were to cascade several filters
过滤，如果我们要级联几个过滤器
with this frequency response then because we have things plotted on a boat
这个频率响应，那么，因为我们的东西绘制在一条船
reply
回复
the body plot for the Cascade would simply be summing these and so
身体积为级联会简单地总结这些，所以
if we castigated for example two stages
如果我们痛骂例如两个阶段
is that a role of at 10 dB per decade it would
是，在每十年10分贝它会作用
role of at 20 DB for decades
角色在20分贝数十年
now filters that this type RC filters
现在过滤器，这种类型的RC滤波器
perhaps several of them in cascade are
也许是其中几个级联的
in fact very prevalent
其实很普遍
and in fact in a in a an environment
而事实上在一个在一个环境
like this where where in fact doing recording
像这样的地方在那里，其实这样做记录
we see there there are
我们看到有有
filters a fact I there show up very commonly both in the audio
过滤器的事实我有两个在音频显示非常普遍
and the video poker portion or the signal processing this Associated
和视频扑克部分或信号处理此相关
with making this set of tapes in fact
以使这一套，其实磁带
are let's take a look in the control room
都让我们一起来看看在中控室
and what I'll be able to show you in the control room
什么，我就可以告诉你在中控室
is the audio portion love
是音频部分的爱
the processing that's done and the kinds of filters very much of the type we just
这样做了和种滤镜非常多的类型的处理，我们只
talked about
谈起
their associated with signal processing this stunning
他们与信号处理相关的这个惊人
in preparing the audio the tapes so
在准备音频磁带等等
let's just take a walk into the control room and see what we see
让我们只取一走进控制室，看到我们所看到的
well this is the control room issues for camera switching its
嗯，这是控制室的问题相机的切换
use for computer editing and also audio control
使用电脑编辑，也音频控制
you can see the monitors and these are used for the
你可以看到显示器，这些都是用于
camera switching and and this is the computer editing
相机开关和，这是计算机编辑
console that use for online and offline computer editing
控制台使用在线和离线电脑编辑
but I really want to demonstrate though in a context to the lecture is the audio
但我真的很想在上下文来讲课，虽然证明是音频
control panel
控制面板
which contains among other things a variety of filters for high frequency
其中包含其中包括各种滤波器高频
low frequencies cetera basically equalization
低频率等等基本上均等化
filters and what we have in the way of filtering is
过滤器和我们所拥有的在滤波的方式是
first of all a was referred to as a graphic equalizer
首先一个被称为图形均衡器
which consists of a set a bandpass filters which are described
它包括其中描述了一组带通滤波器的
little more carefully in a minute and then also
稍微仔细一分钟，然后又
and audio Control Panel which is down here
音频控制面板是到这里
and which contains separate equalizer circuits for each
其中包含对每个单独的均衡器电路
over a whole set of channels and also lotsa controls on them
过了一整套对他们的渠道，也lotsa控制
well let me begin in the demonstration by
也让我开始在示范
demonstrating a little bit of what the graphic equalizer does
展示什么样的图形均衡器做一点点
okay well what we have is a set a bandpass filters
还好以及我们所拥有的是一组带通滤波器
and what's indicated appear the center frequencies as the filters
和什么指示出现在中心频率为过滤器
and then a slider switch reach 18 Lexus attenuator amplify
然后一个滑动开关达到18雷克萨斯衰减器类放大
and this is a DP scale so essentially
这是一个DP规模，基本上
if you look across this banker filters
如果你看一下在这个银行家过滤器
with the output olaf for the equalizer just being the summer the outputs from
与输出奥拉夫只是作为夏天的产出从均衡器
you to these filters interestingly the position the slider switches as you move
您将这些有趣的过滤器，当您移动的位置滑块开关
across here
这里对面
in effect shows you what the frequency response to the equalizer is
实际上告诉你什么样的频率响应的均衡器
so you can change the overall shaping I'll
这样你就可以改变整个整形我会
the filter by moving the switches up and down all right now the equalizer is
过滤器通过移动交换机上下所有现在的均衡器
outlets
网点
put the equaliser into the circuit and now I I put in this filtering
把均衡器到电路，现在二把这个过滤
characteristic
特点
and what I'd like to demonstrate is filtering
什么，我想证明的是滤波
with this when we do things that are a little more dramatic than what would
这个时候我们做的事情是不是会是什么多了几分戏剧性
normally be done in a typical audio recordings setting
通常可在一个典型的录音设置完成
and to do this let's add to my voice to music too
而做到这一点，让我们添加至我的声音的音乐太
make it more interesting a not the my voice is an interesting as it is
使它更有趣一个不是我的声音是一个有趣的，因为它是
but in any case let's bring some music up
但在任何情况下，让我们把一些音乐达
and now what all do is
现在什么都做的是
set the low frequencies flat and let me take out the high frequencies
设置低频率平坦，让我拿出高频率
above eight hundred cycle and
上述八百周期和
so now we have affectively is the low-pass filter it
所以现在我们情感上的低通滤波器时，
and now the low-pass filter let me know
现在的低通滤波器让我知道
bring the high is backup
带来高是备份
and so on bringing up those bandpass filters
等造就的带通滤波器
and now let me cut-out the lows
现在让我切出的低点
and you'll hear the lows disappearing and in effect
你会听到的低点消失，实际上
keeping the highest affectively Crispin's
保持最高的情感上克里斯平的
the sound my voice music
声音我的声音的音乐
and finally let me go back 20db equalization I need to the filters
终于让我回去20分贝均衡，我需要的过滤器
and what also to now is
还什么现在是
take the equalizer out at the circuit totally
采取均衡出在电路完全
now let's take a look at the audio Master Control Panel
现在让我们来看看在音频主控面板
and this panel has of course
这个面板，当然有
for each channel and for example channel that we're working on
每个通道，为此我们正在努力的例子通道
a volume control I can turn the volume down
音量控制，我可以把音量调低
and I can turn the volume up and
我可以调高音量和
it also has a set for this particular equalizer circuit
它也有一组针对这个特定的均衡器电路
it has a set love 3 bandpass filters
它拥有一套爱3带通滤波器
and not switch lettuce either
而不是切换生菜要么
put in up to 12 the be gain
把多达12个的BE收益
or 12 DB attenuation in each of the bands
或12分贝的衰减在每个频带
and also a selector switch the lights is select the center the band
也是一个选择开关灯是选择中间的带
so let me Jess a again demonstrate a little bit with this and
所以让我一个杰斯再次证明这一点，并
let's get a closeup of this panel so what we have is i indicated
让我们得到这个面板的特写所以我们所拥有的是我指示的
is 3 bandpass filters and these knobs that I'm pointing to hear
3带通滤波器和这些旋钮是我指着听
are controls that allow us to reach the filters to put in
是控制，使我们能够达到的过滤器，以把
up to 12 dB gain or 12 dB attenuation
高达12 dB的增益或12 dB衰减
there are also with the to the filters a selector switch
也有与该过滤器的选择器开关
that lets us adjust the center frequency the filter basically it's a
让我们调整中心频率的滤波器，基本上它是一个
to position switch they're also as you can see is
定位开关他们也正如你所看到的是
a button dead Lexus either put the equalization in or out
一个按钮死雷克萨斯要么把均衡或缩小
currently the equalization is out but put the equalization in
目前的均衡，但是还是把在均衡
we won't be here any effect from that because the game controls are all set at
我们不会在这里从任何影响，因为游戏控制都设置在
0db
0分贝
and I want to illustrate shortly the effective these but before I do let me
我想说明在短期内有效，但这些之前，我让我
draw your attention
提请您注意
to one other filter which is
到另外一个过滤器，它是
this white switch and this this which
这个白色的开关，这本该
is a high pass filter that essentially
是一个高通滤波器，其本质上
cuts out frequencies below about a hundred cycle so what it means is that
削减了以下的频率大约一百如此循环是什么意思是，
but put this which in everything is more or less flat above a hundred cycles
但把这个这一切都或多或少平以上百次
and what that's used for basically is to eliminate
什么是是用于主要是为了消除
perhaps 60 cycle noise if that's present or some
也许是60周期的噪音，如果这是现在或一些
low-frequency home or whatever well we won't
低频家里或什么以及我们将不
really demonstrate anything with that let so now with the equalization and
真的证明与任何让那么现在的均衡和
demonstrate the effect I'll
演示效果，我将
boosting or attenuating the low and high frequencies
增强或减弱的低频和高频
and again I think for to demonstrate this it's
又一次我认为要证明这一点它的
it illustrates the point the best if a if we have a little background music so
它说明了一点最好，如果，如​​果我们有一点点的背景音乐等等
maestro if you can bring that up
艺术大师，如果你能提起这件事
and so now I'm gonna do is first
所以现在我要做的就是第一
whose the low frequencies and that's what this
它的低频，这就是这个
potentiometer knob will do so now I'll
电位器旋钮将现在这样做我会
increasing the low-frequency game
增加低频游戏
and in fact all the way up to 12 the be when I have the novel
而事实上一路攀升到12的时候被我的小说
was liza going here and so that has a very basic
被莉莎打算在这里等，有一个很基本的
sounding back
冠冕堂皇的背
make it even base you're fighting
使其更立足你战斗
my sees and
我看到并
attenuating knows by
衰减知悉
well
好
okay well leads words some the high-frequency
还好以及导致一些话高频
back in
早在
in now let's turn the low-frequency
在现在让我们把低频
game offers back down
游戏提供回落
20 and now we're back to flat equalization
20，现在我们又回到了平均衡
and now I can turn the low-frequency game down
现在我可以把低频场比赛下来
so dead attenuate the low frequencies by as much as 12 the
所以死了多达12的衰减低频
that's where we are now in service
这就是我们现在在服务
force much first
强制多首
to enhance the highs even more hike in addition coming out who's the highs
提升高点，除了更加息出来谁是高点
by his
他
okay well let's turn down the music now and
还好还有让我们掉头向下的音乐和现在
and go back to no equalization by setting these knives 20 dB in fact we
然后回到没有均衡通过设置其实这些刀20分贝我们
can take the equalizer out
可以采取均衡出
well thats a quick look at some real-world filters
还有那快速浏览一下一些现实世界的过滤器
now let's the stop having so much fun and
现在，让我们有这么多的乐趣和停止
let's go back to the lecture okay well
让我们回到演讲好吗好
thats a little behind the scenes look but I'd
那是一个小幕后看但我
like to do now is turn our attention to
想现在要做的就是把我们的注意力
discrete-time filters and
离散时间滤波器和
as i've mentioned in previous lectures their are
正如我在以前的讲座已经提到的
basically two classes
基本上是两班
love discrete-time filters or discrete time difference equations
爱离散时间滤波器或离散时间差分方程
one class is referred to
一类被称为
as a nonrecourse ive or moving average
作为一种无追索权的香港专业教育学院或移动平均线
filter and the basic idea
滤波器和基本思路
with the moving average filter is something that perhaps your
与移动平均滤波器是，也许你的东西
some what familiar with intuitively think I've the notion
有些什么熟悉的直觉认为我的观点
I love taking that data sequence and
我爱拍照的数据序列和
let's suppose that what we wanted to do was apply a some smoothing to the data
让我们假设我们想要做的是什么应用一些平滑的数据
sequence
序列
we could for example think taking adjacent points
我们可以例如认为服用相邻点
averaging them together and then moving that average
平均在一起，然后移动平均
along the data sequence what you can kinda see intuitively
沿数据序列可以有点明白直观
is that that would have apply some smoothing so in fact
是，这将会应用一些平滑所以实际上
the difference equation let's say for a three-point moving average
差分方程假设为三点均线
would be the difference equation that I indicate here
将差分方程，我在此说明
just simply taking a data point
只是简单地把一个数据点
and the two data points adjacent to it
和两个数据点与其相邻的
and forming an average over those three
并形成平均超过这三个
so if we thought if the kinda processing involved
因此，如果我们想，如果所涉及的还挺处理
if performing an output sequence value
如果执行一个输出序列值
we would take three adjacent points an average though
我们将采取三个相邻点的平均，虽然
that would give us the output at The Associated time
这将使我们在相关的时间输出
and then to compute the next output point we were just simply slide this
然后计算下一个输出点，我们只是简单地滑入这个
by a one-point average these together and that would give us the next output
通过一个单点这些平均起来，这将使我们的下一个输出
point and we would continue along
点，我们将继续沿着
just simply sliding in averaging
只是简单的滑动平均
to form the output data sequence now
现在，以形成输出的数据序列
that's an example love what's commonly referred to as a three-point moving
这是一个例子爱什么通常被称为三点移动
average
平均
in fact we can generalize that notion
其实我们可以概括这一概念
in a number of ways one-way generalizing
在许多方面单向泛化
the notion over moving average from the three-point moving average which I
从以上三点移动平均线移动平均线的概念，我
summarize again here is to think or extending that
这里再总结一下，是思考或延长了
to a larger number of points and in fact
向的点的数量较多，而事实上
applying waits to that as i indicate here
申请需要等待，当我在此说明
so that in addition to just summing up the points and dividing by the number of
因此，除了刚刚总结点和由数除以
points on
点上
we can in fact apply individual weights to the points
我们其实可以适用于个人的权重给分
so that its what is often referred to as awaiting
使得其什么是通常被称为等待
with moving average and I show
与均线和我展示
below one possible kind of curve
下一个可能的一种曲线
that might result where these would-be
这可能会导致这些地方想成为
essentially the weights Associated with this waited
本质上与此相关的权重守
moving average and in fact its easy to verify
移动平均线，而事实上它很容易验证
that this indeed corresponds to the impulse response
这的确对应于脉冲响应
the filter well just two
过滤器也只有两个
cement this notion let me show you an example or two
巩固这个概念让我给你举个例子，两个
here is an example all a
这里有一个例子全部
five-point moving average a five-point moving average
五点的移动平均的五点均线
would have an impulse response dead
将有一个脉冲响应死
just consists of a rectangle Lovelinks 5
只是由一个矩形Lovelinks 5
and if this is convolved with the data sequence that would corresponding
并且，如果这是卷积的数据序列，将对应
correspond to taking five adjacent points and in effect averaging them
对应于服用5相邻点和有效平均它们
we've looked previously at the quarry a transformer this rectangular sequence
我们已经在采石场前面看了一个变压器这个矩形序列
and the forty a transformer that in fact
和40的变压器，实际上
is all the form of a sign an axe over
已经结束的标志斧头的所有形式
sin x kar and as you can see
罪x家和你可以看到
that is so approximation to
是这样的近似
a low-pass filter and so this again is
一个低通滤波器，所以这又是
a the impulse response and frequency response
一个脉冲响应和频率响应
all a non-ideal low-pass filter
所有的非理想的低通滤波器
now there are a variety of both
现在有各种各样的两个
algorithms that in fact tell you how to choose the weights
算法，其实告诉你如何选择权重
associated with the waiting weighted moving average
与等待加权移动平均相关
to in some sense design better approximations
在一定意义上设计出更好的近似值
and without going into the details love any of those algorithms
并没有进入细节爱任何这些算法
let me just show the results of choosing the weights
让我只显示选择的权重结果
for the design over 250 first 251 points
为设计超过250首251点
moving average filter where the weights
移动平均滤波器，其中的权重
are chosen using an optimum algorithm to generate a sharp a cut-off
利用优化算法来生成一个尖锐的截止被选择
as can possibly be generated and so what I show here
因为都不可能产生，所以我在这里展示
is the frequency response
是频率响应
that the resulting filter on a logarithmic ample to scale
这对数足够规模的结果过滤器
in a linear frequency scale noticed that on this scale the pass band is very flat
在一个线性频率刻度注意到，这种规模的通带是非常平坦
although here is an expanded you all that and in fact it
虽然这里是一个扩大你一切，事实上它
has was referred to as an equal ripple characteristic
一直被称为等波纹特性
and then here's the transition band and here we have to stop and
然后这里的过渡带，在这里我们必须停止和
which in fact is down somewhat more than 80 dB
这实际上是下降较为80 dB以上
and again has what's referred to as an equal ripple characterised
并再次有什么被称为等波纹特点
now the notion of a moving average
现在的移动平均的概念
for filtering is something dead is very commonly
过滤是死的东西是很常用
use I a head shown last time actually the result
用我一个头显示最后一次实际的结果
some filtering on a particular data sequence the Dow Jones Industrial
在一个特定的数据序列，道琼斯工业一些过滤
Average
平均
and very often in
而且往往在
looking at various kinds a stock market publications
看着各种股市出版物
what you will see is this the Dow Jones average
你会看到这是道琼斯指数
shown in its raw form as a data sequence and then very typically
作为一个数据序列，然后很典型的在其原始形式显示
you you'll see also: the result all
你，你还会看到：结果所有
moving average where the moving average might
移动平均线移动平均威力
be on the order love days or it might be on the order
是在为了爱天，或者它可能是为了在
months the whole notion being to take
个月的整个概念是采取
some other random high frequency fluctuations
其他一些随机的高频率波动
out at the average and show the low-frequency
出的平均，并显示低频
or trends over
或长期趋势
some period of time so let's
一段时间让我们
in fact go back to the Dow Jones average and
其实回去道琼斯指数和
let me now show you what the result of filtering
现在让我告诉你什么滤波的结果
with a moving average filter would look like
与移动平均滤波器会是什么样子
on the Seder same Dow Jones Industrial Average sequence that I showed last time
在家宴同一道琼斯工业平均指数序列，我发现最后一次
so once again we have the Dow Jones average from 1927 to roughly 1932
因此，我们再次道琼斯指数从1927年到1932年大约
at the top we see the impulse response for the moving average
在上面我们看到了移动平均的脉冲响应
again I remind you on an expanded time scale
我再次提醒你，在扩大规模的时间
and was shown here is the moving average with just one point
这里被证明是移动平均只用一个点
so the output on the bottom trace is
所以在底部跟踪输出
just simply identical to the input now let's increase the link to the moving
只是简单地等同于输入现在让我们来增加链接到移动
average 22 points and we see that there's a small amount of smoothing
平均22点，我们看到，有少量的平滑
three points and just a little more smoothing pickets inserted
三个点并插入一点点平滑纠察队
now a four-point moving average
现在是四点移动平均线
and next the five-point moving average
和旁边的五点移动平均线
and a six-point moving average next we see that the smoothing increases
和六点均线接下来我们看到，平滑的增加
now let's increase the link to the moving average filter much more rapidly
现在让我们来增加链接到移动平均滤波器更迅速
and watch how the output is
并观察输出
more and more smooth in relation to the input
越来越多的平滑就输入
again i emphasize that the timescale
我再次强调，时间尺度
for the impulse response is significantly expanded in relationship
对脉冲响应的关系显著扩大
to the timescale for both the input in the output
在输出时标为输入
and once again through the magic of filtering we've been able to eliminate
并再次通过过滤的魔力，我们已经能够消除
the 1929 stock market crash
1929年的股市崩盘
alright so we've seen moving average filters
好吧，所以我们已经看到了移动平均滤波器
and or what are sometimes referred to as
和，或什么都有时也被称为
non workers is filters and
非工作人员是过滤器和
they are as I stressed very important class
他们是因为我强调很重要的类
discreet I filters another
我谨慎的另一个过滤器
very important class of discrete-time filters are
离散时间滤波器非常重要的一类是
what are referred to as rehearses filters
什么被称为排练滤波器
workers the filters are filters that for which the difference equation
工人的过滤器是过滤器，对于其差分方程
has feedback from the output back
有从输出反馈回
into the input in other words the output
到输入换句话说，输出
depends not only on the input but also on previous values if the output
不仅依赖于输入，而且对以前的值，如果输出
so for example as i stress previously
因此，例如像我以前强调
a rikers a difference equation has
一个赖克斯一个差分方程有
the general form that I indicate year
一般形式，我表示一年
a linear combination love waited outputs on the left hand side and linear
的线性组合的爱等待输出在左手侧和线性
combination
组合
waited inputs on the right hand side and
等待输入在右手侧和
as we talked about we can solve this equation
当我们谈到，我们可以解这个方程
for the current output why I have an interns a
对于电流输出，为什么我有一个实习生
of current and past inputs and passed out
当前和过去的输入，并通过了
what's for example just two
什么是例如只有两个
interpret this focus on the interpretation of this is a filter
解释这个注重这个的解释是一个过滤器
let's looking at a first-order difference equation which
让我们看一个一阶差分方程，
we've talked about and generated the solution to previously
我们已经讨论过，并产生解决以前
so the first-order a first 30 difference equation
因此第一阶第一30差分方程
would be as i indicated here
就正如我在这里
and imposing causality on this
并在此强加因果关系
so that we assume that we are running this is a recursion forward in time
让我们假设我们正在运行的这个时间向前是一个递归
we can solve this for why I have an intern's affects it man
我们可以解决这个为什么我有一个实习生的影响它的人
and why I have and -1 waited
为什么我已经和等待-1
by the factor a and I simply indicate
由一个因素，我只是表明
the block diagram for this but what we want to examine now
该框图这一点，但我们现在要探讨
for this first order recursion is the frequency response and see its
这种一阶递归的频率响应和看到它的
interpretation
解释
as a filter well in fact again
作为过滤器也实际上再次
the mathematics for this we've gone through in the last lecture
我们在上一讲中经历了数学这
and so interpreting the first-order difference equation as a system
等解释一阶差分方程作为系统
we can what what we're attempting to
我们可以我们正在尝试什么
generate is the frequency response
产生的是频率响应
which is the forty a transformer the impulse response
它是40的变压器的脉冲响应
and from the difference equation we can of course all
并从差分方程，我们都可以，当然
for either one of those by using the properties exploiting the properties in
对于那些任何一个使用物业开发物业
for EA transform applying to 48 transport to the difference equation
对EA变换应用到48运输到差分方程
we will end up with the forty a transformer the output
我们将最终获得第四十一个变压器的输出
equal to the Fourier transform the input times this factor which
等于傅立叶变换的输入的时间这一因素而
we know from the convolution property in fact
我们从实际上卷积物业知道
is the frequency response
是频率响应
of the system so this is the frequency response
系统，所以这是频率响应
and of course the inverse Fourier transform a bad
当然和傅立叶逆变换的坏
which I E indicate below
我E分别表示如下
is the system impulse response
是该系统的脉冲响应
so we have the frequency response obtained by
因此我们必须由获得的频率响应
applying to free a transformed to the difference equation the impulse response
采用以释放转化为差分方程的脉冲响应
and as we did last time we can
和我们做最后一次，我们可以
look at that interns love
看那个实习生的爱
a frequency response characteristic
的频率响应特性
and recall that depending on whether
并记得取决于
the factor A is positive or negative we need to get
的因子A是正还是负，我们需要得到
a low-pass filter or a high pass filter
一个低通滤波器或高通滤波器
and if in fact we look at the frequency response
如果事实上我们看的频率响应
for the factor a being positive then we see that this is an approximation
对于因子a是正的，那么我们可以看到，这是一个近似
to a low-pass filter who wears below it I showed the frequency response
到一个低通滤波器，谁穿它下面我展示的频率响应
for a negative & mare the
对于负和母马的
this corresponds to a way high pass filter because we're attenuating
这相当于一种高通滤波器，因为我们正在减弱
low frequencies and retaining
低频率和保留
the high frequencies in and
在高频率中，并
recall also that we illustrated
还记得，我们说明
this this characteristic as a low-pass high-pass filter for the recursion
这此特性作为一个低通高通滤波器，用于递归
for the first-order recursion by by looking at
对于一阶递归由通过观察
how it work as a filter in both cases
在这两种情况下作为一个过滤器如何工作
when the input was the Dow Jones average and indeed we saw that
当输入是道琼斯指数而事实上，我们看到，
it generated both low-pass and high-pass filtering
它生成的两个低通和高通滤波
in in the appropriate cases so for discrete-time
在适当的情况下，所以对于离散时间
we have the two classes moving average and
我们有两个类均线和
a cursive filters and
草书过滤器和
and there are a variety of issues discussed in the text about why
并有各种各样的问题，有关文本讨论了为什么
in certain contexts one might want to use one or the other basically what
在某些情况下人们可能希望使用一个或另一个基本上是什么
happens
发生
is dead for the moving average filter
是死了的移动平均滤波器
for a given set a filter specifications there are many more multiplications
对于一个给定的过滤器规格有更多的乘法
required in for a cursive filter by
通过在需要的草书过滤器
there are in certain contexts some very important compensating benefits
还有在某些情况下一些很重要的补偿效益
the moving average filter
移动平均滤波器
now this concludes pretty much
现在这个结论几乎
what I A want to say in detail
我一想详细说
about filtering the concept filtering in this set of lectures
关于过滤的概念滤波这套讲座
this is only a very quick glimpse into
这只是一个非常快速的一瞥
a very important and very rich topic and one of course that
当然是一个非常重要和非常丰富的主题和一个
can be studied on its own in considerable amount of detail
可以研究其本身在相当数量的细节
as the lectures go online what will find
作为讲课去网上会有什么发现
is that the basic concept to filtering both
是，基本概念来过滤两
ideal and non-ideal filtering will will
理想和非理想的过滤会会
be a very important part love what we do
是一个非常重要的组成部分热爱我们做什么
and in in particular
和在特定
beginning with the next lecture will turn to
下一个演讲开始将转向
a discussion of modulation exploiting
调制利用的讨论
the property modulation as it relates to some practical problems
因为它涉及到一些实际问题的财产调制
and what will find when we do that is that
什么会发现，当我们这样做是
a very important part of that discussion and in fact the very important part
这一讨论的和其实是一个很重要的部分，很重要的一部分
love the use of modulation also
爱用调制也
just naturally incorporates the concept
只是自然融合的概念
and properties filtering thank you
和属性过滤谢谢